

- dickmbeya@gmail.com
- www.dicksonmbeya.com
- Blantyre city, Malawi

EDUCATION

BSc. Earth Sciences

University of Malawi 2011 - 2015

MSc. in Biodiversity Informatics

Malawi University of Science and Technology 2021 - 2024

EXPERTISE

Cartography

GIS

Remote Sensing

Spatial Biodiversity Assessments

Geology

Informatics

LANGUAGE

English

Chichewa

Tumbuka

DICKSON MBEYA

Cartographer

ABOUT ME

I am an award-winning cartographer and an experienced geospatial professional with more than a decade of experience in utilizing geospatial technologies to derive information products. I have 7 plus years experience teaching GIS and Remote Sensing in a higher learning institution.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Q Jan 2023- Present

Malawi University of Science and Technology | Malawi

Project Manager and Spatial Assessment Lead

Overseeing project activities and leading spatial assessment in the "Building biodiversity knowledge for action in Southern Africa: Spatial Biodiversity Assessment, Prioritization and Planning(SBAPP) in South Africa, Namibia, Mozambique and Malawi" project at national level.

o 2017 - Present

Malawi University of Science and Technology | Malawi

Cartography Technician

I manage the University's Laboratory of Geo-Information Science and Remote Sensing. My work involves developing and teaching GIS, Remote Sensing and Cartography practical work using commercial and open-source GIS software including QGIS and ArcGIS.

May 2017 - September 2017
PricewaterhouseCoopers

Temporary Registration Officer

Captured national identification data into the National Registration Information System.